harrisburgu.edu 2019-03-03

# 

                   Harrisburg University of Science and Technology
                                          Privacy Notice
Harrisburg University of Science and Technology (HU) is committed to safeguarding the privacy
of individuals who share personal data with it. This Privacy Notice outlines HU’s collection, use,
and disclosure of Information provided by prospective students, applicants, or third parties. You
understand and agree that HU may collect, use, and disclose Information as described in this
Privacy Notice.
                         HOW HU COLLECTS YOUR INFORMATION
HU may collect your personal data in a number of ways, for example:
    •   When you interact with HU before applying or enrolling, for example when you express
        your interest in studying here;
    •   When you apply for admission to HU, or otherwise provide HU with Information in your
        application for admission,
    •   When you complete enrollment forms with HU;
    •   When you communicate with HU by telephone, email or use HU’s websites and other
        services; and
    •   From third parties, for example from your previous or current school, from testing
        agencies, or from employers or other individuals who may provide a reference about you.
                             INFORMATION COLLECTED BY HU
As part of the application process, HU collects general information from or about you such as:
    •   Your name, address, phone number, email address, and date of birth. HU may also assign
        you a unique student identification number.
    •   Education and employment history, such as the schools you have attended, places you have
        worked, courses completed, grades, standardized test scores, and other Information in your
        student record.
    •   Information about your family and social circumstances, academic and extracurricular
        interests and, with respect to financial aid, financial details. For purposes of this Privacy
        Notice, Information refers to all Information other than Sensitive Information that you have
        provided to the Admissions in your application.
As part of the application process, HU may also collect Sensitive Information from or about
you. For purposes of this Privacy Notice, Sensitive Information is defined as race or ethnic origin,
political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, union membership, data concerning health or
sex life and sexual orientation, criminal convictions, and genetic data or biometric data.

                                                                                                    2
                            UNIVERSITY USE OF INFORMATION
HU will use Information that you provide to it and Information it collects about you to administer
your application or for your matriculation at HU. In addition, HU may use your Information to
analyze and improve its admission process, for outreach efforts, and for other University processes
and functions related to your admission and matriculation as a student. HU may also de-identify
your Sensitive Information to use for research or statistical purposes. If you are enrolled as a
student of HU, HU may use and share your Information internally with other HU offices and units
to support your success as a student and to deliver education, advising, residence, athletic, student
development, support services (e.g., health and careers), financial assistance, security, and for
fundraising. Sensitive Information will only be used when needed, such as use of your health
information to provide any necessary accommodations.
                                      ONLINE PAYMENTS
HU may collect credit card Information from you for your application fee, enrollment deposit,
tuition, and other attendance costs. A reputable third-party financial institution handles HU’s credit
card transactions.
                 HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES
We may disclose your Information to third parties as follows:
Consent. HU may use and disclose your Information and Sensitive Information to third parties if
we have your consent to do so.
Parents and Guardians. In some cases, HU may share your Information with a parent or guardian
if necessary to properly complete the admission process or in the event of an emergency.
Service Providers. HU may use third parties to support its operations such the National Student
Clearinghouse; Howell Management Services (HMS), and Ruffalo Noel Levitz. In such cases, HU
may share your Sensitive Information and Information with these third parties who are obligated
to safeguard it from unauthorized disclosure.
The privacy statements of HU’s third parties can be found at the following links:
     •   National Student Clearinghouse:
         http://www.studentclearinghouse.org/about/privacy_commitment.php
     •   HMS:
         https://www.howellmgmt.com/
     •   Ruffalo Noel Levitz:
         https://www.ruffalonl.com/privacy-policy/
Employment Necessity. HU may share your Information and Sensitive Information when
necessary if you are employed by the University, in accordance with applicable law subject to the
imposition of appropriate safeguards to prevent further unauthorized disclosure.
Rev.9/10/2018

                                                                                                    3
School Counselors and Administrators. HU may use your Information and share it with your
school counselors and administrators who have a legitimate educational interest in the data.
Public Information. HU may share your Information or Sensitive Information if you have
manifestly made it public.
Archiving. HU may share your Information and Sensitive Information for archiving purposes in
the public interest, historical research, and statistical purposes.
Performance of a Contract. HU may share your Information when necessary to administer a
contract you have with the University.
University Affiliated Programs. HU may share your Information with third parties that are
affiliated with it for contacting you about goods, services, or experiences that may be of interest
to you.
Research and Studies. HU may share your Information with third parties that study admission or
other topics related to higher education. It may also share your Information with third parties that
conduct research or develop products or services designed to improve admission and other higher
education functions.
Required by Law. HU may share your Information with third parties to the extent we are required
to do so by law, court order, or subpoena.
Emergency Circumstances. HU may share your Information or Sensitive Information with third
parties if, in our sole judgment, such disclosure is necessary to protect the health, safety, or
property of any person.
De-Identified and Aggregate Information. HU may collect, use and disclose Sensitive
Information or other Information about our applicants in de-identified or aggregate form without
limitation.
                                             SECURITY
You must have a secure browser—one that supports secure transmission of data across the
Internet—to apply online to HU. For more Information about your browser’s security features, use
your browser’s help feature. HU implements appropriate technical and organizational security
measures to protect your Information when you transmit it to the University and when HU stores
it on our Information technology systems.
                      HU’S BASES TO PROCESS YOUR INFORMATION
HU processes Information and Sensitive Information as it is necessary for the performance of the
contract under which it provides services to students. Some of HU’s processing activities may also
be carried out under a legal obligation, where it is necessary to protect the vital interests of HU’s
students or another party, or for legitimate interests pursued by HU or a third party. HU may also
process Information or Sensitive Information based on your consent.
              RETENTION AND DESTRUCTION OF YOUR INFORMATION
Your Information will be retained by HU in accordance with applicable federal laws, and HU
record retention policies. Your Information will be destroyed upon your request or after the
Rev.9/10/2018

                                                                                                       4
expiration of the applicable retention period required by law, whichever is later. The manner of
destruction shall be appropriate to preserve and ensure the confidentiality of your Information
given the level of sensitivity, value and criticality to HU.
                                          YOUR RIGHTS
You have the right to request access to, a copy of, rectification, restriction in the use of, or erasure
of your Information. These rights differ depending upon the location within the world where
Information and Sensitive Information was created or shared. You also have the right to withdraw
consent to the use of your Sensitive Information, which will not affect the lawfulness of HU’s use
prior to receipt of your request. Certain Information may be exempt from such requests in some
circumstances, which may include if we need to keep processing your Information for HU’s
legitimate interests or to comply with a legal obligation. HU may request that you provide
Information necessary to confirm your identity before responding to your request. You may
exercise these rights by contacting HU’s Data Manager at: helpdesk@harrisburgu.edu or 717-901-
5177.
If your Information and Sensitive Information was created within or transferred from the European
Union, you may also be able to file a complaint with the appropriate supervisory authority in the
European Union.
                                  UPDATES TO THIS NOTICE
We may update or change this Notice at any time. Your continued use of HU’s site after any such
change indicates your acceptance of such changes.
Rev.9/10/2018
